<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>teaching.ookb.co</title>
    <description>teaching.ookb.co</description>
    <link>http://teaching.ookb.co</link>
    <pubDate>2013-10-13</pubDate>
    <item>
      <title>Animatic</title>
      <link>http://teaching.ookb.co/glossary/a/animatic</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using keyframes from a storyboard and editing and displaying them in sequence with a rough dialogue and/or rough sound track to test whether the sound and images are working effectively together; A rough animated storyboard used to give some idea about the timing of a sequence. Typically for production purposes only.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Animation</title>
      <link>http://teaching.ookb.co/glossary/a/animation</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sequences of still images to create the optical illusion of movement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anticipation</title>
      <link>http://teaching.ookb.co/glossary/a/anticipation</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;something expected (as on the basis of a norm); or the act of predicting&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aspect Ratio</title>
      <link>http://teaching.ookb.co/glossary/a/aspect-ratio</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;the mathematical fraction detailing the relationship between width and hone-third of a piece (e.g. 4:3, 16:9, etc.). Old TVs and Computer Monitors are usually about 4:3&#x2014;a 1024 x 768 monitor is exactly 4:3. Newer &#x201C;Widescreen&#x201D; formats will be a higher ration, 16:9 being a standard american film widescreen format. A common widescreen computer monitor ratio is 8:5.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blocking</title>
      <link>http://teaching.ookb.co/glossary/b/blocking</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;putting in basic timing and poses to communicate where one is going with an animated scene&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Down a Shot</title>
      <link>http://teaching.ookb.co/glossary/b/breaking-down-a-shot</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;carefully explaining, step by step, what happens in a scene &#x2014; part of storyboarding (or reverse storyboarding)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Classical Mechanics</title>
      <link>http://teaching.ookb.co/glossary/c/classical-mechanics</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the two major sub-fields of mechanics, which is concerned with the set of physical laws mathematically describing the motions of bodies under the action of a system of forces. Basically, Classical Mechanics describes everyday motion and forces&#x2014;running, jumping, falling, crashing cars, launching rockets, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Closure</title>
      <link>http://teaching.ookb.co/glossary/c/closure</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Observing the parts but perceiving the whole. It is your brain completing a picture (or scene, or environment, etc.) for you, even though you have only some of the parts &#x2026;  Completing that which is incomplete based on past experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Time</title>
      <link>http://teaching.ookb.co/glossary/d/deep-time</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;the idea of Geological Time; time scales not easily graspable through terms of human lifetimes, or even the span of human history&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exaggeration</title>
      <link>http://teaching.ookb.co/glossary/e/exaggeration</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;representing something as far better or worse than it really is (or far greater, smaller, longer, shorter, faster, slower, farther, nearer &#x2026; whatever)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frame</title>
      <link>http://teaching.ookb.co/glossary/f/frame</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The smallest unit of animation&#x2014;a single still image or other item.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frame-Rate</title>
      <link>http://teaching.ookb.co/glossary/f/frame-rate</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The number of frames displayed per second for a given animation. This is typically labelled as FPS &#x2014;&#xA0;as in Frames-per-second. About 30 FPS (actually 29.97 fps) for normal American TV. For stop-motion or frame-by-frame animation you need at least 12 FPS to make any motion seem semi-smooth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frame-by-Frame</title>
      <link>http://teaching.ookb.co/glossary/f/frame-by-frame</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Animation style where every single frame is created on its own. This would be traditional animation, stop-motion, clay-mation, flipbooks, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpolation</title>
      <link>http://teaching.ookb.co/glossary/i/interpolation</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;a message that is introduced or inserted &#x2014; often a viewer does this themselves into something you&#x2019;ve created&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keyframe</title>
      <link>http://teaching.ookb.co/glossary/k/keyframe</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first + last frames of each short action sequence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Motion</title>
      <link>http://teaching.ookb.co/glossary/m/motion</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Change over Time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Narrative</title>
      <link>http://teaching.ookb.co/glossary/n/narrative</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;an acount; a tale; a story&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Newton&#x2019;s Laws</title>
      <link>http://teaching.ookb.co/glossary/n/newtons-laws</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The three laws that form the basis for Classical Mechanics. They enable the prediction of the path of any object from a grain of sand to a planet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A body will remain at rest or move with a constant velocity unless acted upon by an outside force.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The acceleration of a body is proportional to the applied force. This is expressed by the universal formula: Force = mass &#xD7; acceleration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For every action there is an equal and opposite reaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pacing</title>
      <link>http://teaching.ookb.co/glossary/p/pacing</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Speed of action or events.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Persistence of Vision</title>
      <link>http://teaching.ookb.co/glossary/p/persistence-of-vision</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The phenomenon of the eye by which an afterimage is thought to persist for approximately one twenty-fifth of a second on the retina. A Newton disc takes advantage of this principle, as do most animation techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
